[{"answerkey":3,"option 3":"To find defects in the software application","option 4":"To test only the UI layer","question":"What is the main objective of manual testing?","option 1":"To replace automation tools","option 2":"To ensure 100% code coverage"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":"Waterfall Testing","option 4":"Integration Testing","question":"Which of the following is NOT a type of testing?","option 1":"Smoke Testing","option 2":"Unit Testing"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":" Test steps, input data, expected result","option 4":" Only the test summary","question":"What does a test case typically include?","option 1":"Only the expected result","option 2":"Only the input data"},{"answerkey":2,"option 3":"Test Planning → Test Closure → Test Execution","option 4":"Test Case Design → Requirement Analysis → Test Planning","question":"What is the correct order of the Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC)?","option 1":"Test Execution → Test Planning → Test Design","option 2":"Requirement Analysis → Test Planning → Test Case Design → Test Execution → Test Closur"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":"Exploratory Testing","option 4":"System Testing","question":"Which type of testing is done without using any test cases or plan?","option 1":"Regression Testing","option 2":"Unit Testing"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":" Retesting after changes to ensure existing functionality works","option 4":"Testing performance under load","question":"What is Regression Testing?","option 1":"Testing to ensure code quality","option 2":"Testing a module in isolation"},{"answerkey":2,"option 3":"Complexity","option 4":"Category","question":"Which of the following defines the impact of a defect on the application?","option 1":"Priority","option 2":"Severity"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":"Validation ensures product meets requirements","option 4":"Verification is dynamic, Validation is static","question":"What is the difference between Validation and Verification?","option 1":"Validation is done before Verification","option 2":"Verification is about actual product testing"},{"answerkey":2,"option 3":"The path of a tester\u2019s role","option 4":"Only tracking open bugs","question":"What is a defect life cycle?","option 1":"Process of writing test case","option 2":"Stages a defect goes through from discovery to closure"},{"answerkey":3,"option 3":"Test Plan","option 4":"Test Script","question":"Which document defines scope, approach, resources, and schedule of testing?","option 1":"Use Case","option 2":"Test Scenario"}]